A Guide to the Doris Zallen Papers, 1952-2016
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Doris Zallen Papers, 1952-2016
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2018-032
10 Cubic Feet; 13 boxes
The collection contains meeting notes from the Recombinant DNA Advisory Committee, Doris Zallen's professional papers, book reviews, and background on Zallen's published papers from 1960 to 2016. Doris Zallen attended Brooklyn College and Harvard University before becaming a professor of Science and Technolgy Studies and Humanities in the College of Liberal Arts and Human Science at Virginia Tech. This collection follows Zallen's acadamic work from the undergraduate to graduate level, post-doctoral appointments, and her genetic research and teaching. Included in this collection is Zallens research on the Liverpool School which providedresearches the medical advance of the prevention of Rh disease.
Zallen, Doris T.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Doris Zallen Papers were donated to Special Collections in July 2018. Additions were donated in March 2019 and December 2019.
Biographical Note
Doris Zallen received her bachelor's degree from Brooklyn College and completed her graduate and doctoral work at Harvard Univeristy. Zallen focused her research on the social, ethical, and policy issues of genetic technologies. She came to Virginia Tech in 1983 and retired as professor of Science and Technology Studies and Humanities in 2015. Zallen published three books and created the Choices and Challenges Forum series at Virginia Tech. In 1991 Zallen interviewed David Weatherall who sparked Zallen's research on the prevention of Rh disease and the role the Liverpool School played in that medical advance.
Scope and Content
The Doris Zallen Papers, Ms2018-032, contain content from Doris Zallen's professional work with genetic research, discussions, and testing from 1960 to 2016.
The records are divided into six series including: I. Recombinant DNA Advisory Committee Service, 1990-1999; II. Professional Papers, 1960-2016; III. Book Reviews, 1962-2010; IV. Background information on Published Papers, 1980-2008; V. Ethics and Advisory Board, 1979; and VI. Liverpool School, 1952-2012.
In the first series, Recombinant DNA Advisory Committee Service, 1990-1999, each folder relates to the Recombinant Advisory Committee. They include meeting notes, correspondence within the organization, and notes from conferences.
The second series, Professional Papers, 1960-2016, outlines Doris Zallen's academia starting with her education at Brooklyn College, Harvard University, and the University of Rochester. This series includes manuscripts from her teaching and research careers at Nazareth College of Rochester and Virginia Tech. Zallen's professional papers include research, summaries of sabbaticals and other leaves, consulting, teaching awards, and student and faculty correspondence.
Series III, Book Reviews, 1962-2010, includes book reviews from other scholars about Zallen's research: "Science and Morality", "Does it Run In the Family?," and "To Test or Not to Test?" This series also includes a poster from a discusion led by Zallen about genetic testing and images from "Does it Run In the Family?"
The fourth series, Background information on Published Papers, 1980-2008, contains published and unpublished articles by Doris Zallen and other scholars about genes from 1980 to 2008.
The fifth series, Ethics and Advisory Board, 1979, consists of the report, conclusions, and appendix from the Human in Vitro Fertilization and Embryo Transfer study.
The last series, Liverpool School, 1952-2012, consists of background information, publications, interviews, and pictures from Zallen's research of the prevention of Rh disease.
Arrangement
The Doris Zallen Papers are organized into the following series:
Series I. Recombinant DNA Advisory Committee (NIH) Service, 1990-1999
Series II. Professional papers, 1960-2016
Series III. Book Reviews, 1982-2010
Series IV. Background Information on Published Papers, 1980-2008
Series V. Ethics Advisory Board, 1979
Series VI. Liverpool School, 1952-2012
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Choices and Challenges Forum Records, RG 15/27/1, Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech.
Philip M. Sheppard Papers, Mss.Ms.Coll.65, American Philosophical Society.
D36/A-J - Sir Cyril Astley Clarke Papers - 1926-2000, Special Collections & Archives, University of Liverpool.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Faculty; Science and Technology; University History; University Archives
Organizations:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Arts and Sciences (?-2003); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Liberal Arts & Human Sciences (2003-)
People:
Zallen, Doris T.
Contents List
- Series I. Recombinant DNA Advisory Committee (NIH) Service, 1990-1999
  - Committee Content
    - RAC Appointment (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - RAC Photographs, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Revised Amendments to I-D and Final Version, 1994-06-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Service on the Verma Committee to Evaluate the RAC, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Other RAC Issues (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Doris Teichler Zallen, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Subcommittee Background and Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - RAC Meeting, 1992-06-01-1992-06-02 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - RAC Meeting, 1992-09-14-1992-09-15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - RAC Meeting, 1992-12-03-1992-12-04 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of Meeting, 1993-01-14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - RAC Meeting, 1993-03-01-1993-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - RAC Meeting, 1993-06-07-1993-06-08 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - RAC Meeting, 1993-09-09-1993-09-10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - RAC Meeting, 1993-12-03-1993-12-04 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - RAC Meeting, 1994-03-03-1994-03-04 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - RAC Meeting, 1994-06-09-1994-06-10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - RAC Meeting, 1994-09-12-1994-09-13 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Gene Therapy, 1994-09-28 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - RAC Meeting, 1994-12-01-1994-12-02 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - RAC Meetings, 1995-03-06-1995-03-07, 1995-06-08-1995-06-09, 1995-09-11-1995-09-12 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - RAC Meeting, 1995-06-08-1995-06-09 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - RAC Meeting, 1995-09-11-1995-09-12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - RAC Meeting and Modifications, 1995-12-04-1995-12-05 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - OTC Protocol, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minor Modifications, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Viagene Materials, 1995-02 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - RAC Meeting, 1995-03-06-1995-03-07 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - RAC Meeting, 1995-06-08-1995-06-09 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - RAC Meeting, 1996-12-09 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Doris Zallen Editorial, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gene Therapy Policy Conference, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - RAC Meeting, 1998-09-24 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Third Gene Therapy Policy Conference, 1999-01-07-1999-01-08 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - RAC Meeting, 1999-09-02 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series II. Professional papers, 1960-2016
  - Brooklyn College (Undergraduate) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Harvard (Graduate), 1961-1966
    - Cell Biology Paper, 1963-01 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Thesis Outline and Notes, 1965-07-29 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Original Drawing For Thesis (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Graphs, Tables, Micrographs from Thesis Folder 1/2 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Statistics Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Graphs, Tables, Micrographs from Thesis Folder 2/2 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Drawings, Micrographs, for paper on Manganese and Structure (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Drawings and Photographs from Paper Cycle E.T. in Algae (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Papers on Photoinhibition of Respiration, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - University of Rochester (post-Doctoral work)
    - Appointments (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - M.D. Research Grant Proposals 1 and 2, 1977-1978, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - M.D.A. Research Grant Proposal, 1979-1980, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Lab Talk, Patient Talk (MDA), 1980-03-20, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Secretor Paper (Final), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Figures, Sketches of Data, Statistics (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Antigen Drawing and Data (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Original Figures (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Photographs and Figures (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Fetal ABO Paper (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Drawings (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Poster, Paper, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Nazareth College of Rochester, 1976-1983
    - Nazareth Letters (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Never Published (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Science and Morality Papers by Speakers, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Science and Morality Conference, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Science and Morality Evening Event, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Science and Morality Speakers, Preprogram, Publicity, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Science and Morality Conference Papers by Speakers, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Science and Morality Speakers, Preprogram, Publicity, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Science and Morality Conference Grant (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - TV Series on Science and Morality, 1982-07-1982-08 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - NYCH Speakers in the Humanities, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Science and Morality Unpublished Volume, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
    - Science and Morality Conference Video, 1981-03-27 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Virginia Tech, 1983-2015
    Scope and Contents
    FARs (Faculty Activities Report) and related doucments
    - Faculty Activities Reports, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Activities Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - CY [Faculty Activities Reports], 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - CY [Faculty Activities Reports], 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - CY [Faculty Activities Reports], 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Promotion and Tenure File, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Personnel File, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Personnel, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Personnel, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Personnel, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Personnel, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Personnel, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Current Personnel, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Faculty Activities Reports, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Faculty Activities Reports and Materials, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Personnel, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Academic Year, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Academic Year, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Personnel, 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Personnel, 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Personnel, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Personnel, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Personnel, 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Personnel, 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Personnel, 2011-2012 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Personnel, 2012-2013 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Academic Year, 2013-2014 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Calendar Year Personnel, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Personnel, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Teaching Materials
    - Sample Syllabi (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Teaching Dossier, 1996-12 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Teaching Certificate Information, Copy of Dossier, 1999-01 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Science Policy Discussion Group, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Op-Ed Articles by Students (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Awards, 2001-08-02 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Ethics Committee Meeting, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Student Comments on Teaching (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Graduate Students (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Samples of Public Writing (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Summaries of Sabbaticals, Leaves, Course Reductions, etc. to Permit Scholarly Work (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Consulting
    - Genetic Health, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Direct Consulting, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Webcast 1 with Peter A. Underhill, 2001-02-28 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Webcast 2 with Robert A. Weinberg, 2001-03-01 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Webcast 3 Genetic Privacy with Rothstein and McCabe, 2001-03-23 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Webcast 4 Genes and Depression with Levinson and Barondes, 2001-03-28 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Webcast 5 Genetic Medicine with McKusick, 2001-05 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - WVTF Evening Edition Program, 2010-02-23 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Awards Received at Virginia Tech
    - Teaching Excellence, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - University Distinguished Professorship Application, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Woodrow Wilson Innovation Awards, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Alumni Outreach Award Dossier, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Outstanding Faculty Award, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence
    - Mel Belsky, 1989-06-29 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence and Interviews with Ernst Caspari, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Letters - Francis Collins (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Richard Doherty MD (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - C. C. Gillespie Letter, 1993-08-20 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Bertrand Goldschmidt (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Daniel S. Greenberg, GraS (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Marjorie Grene (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Joy Harvey (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Mary Jennings (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Elaine Karron (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - London Items and Correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Jane Maienschein (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Diane Rehm Show, 2009-01-08 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Abbey Meyers (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Ursula Mittwoch (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Guil Ross (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - William Schneider (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - C. C. Tan and Chinese Genetics, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Gail Winchester (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Claude Wolff (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Rene Wurmser (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - David Zimmerman (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia
    Includes photographs, newspaper articles, and interviews in the press
    - Newspaper Articles (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Doris Zallen Photographs (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - CDs (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Talks (a representative sample), 1967-2016
    - Colloquium U of R, 1967-04 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Yeast Meeting, Ms of Journal Paper, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Chaos in Reproduction, 1986-10 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - AAAS Symposium on "Human Linkage Testing: The New Ethical Issue" (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - AS2 Meeting: The Shaping of Post-War Genetics in France, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Vet School Research Day - Will Everything That Can Be Done Be Done?, 1990-05 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Chalk Talk, 1990-10-06 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - UK - Leeds Talks, 1991-06-20 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Hunter College, 1992-05-04 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Jean Gayon and Doris Zallen - "Le Role des Vilmorin.." (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - President's Symposium - Articles and Draft of Final Article, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - BioIndustry Assoiciation, London - "Gene Therapy Research in the U.S.: Policy, Programs, and the Public", 1993-11 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Lunch Talk on Gene Therapy and Policy, 1995-04 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - American Society of Human Genetics Meeting, 1996-10-29-1996-11-02 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Indiana University Talk, 1996-11 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Foundation Talk, 1996-11 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - NIH, NINR Talk, Overheads, Correspondence, 1999-03-15, 2000-06-28 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Carilion - Grand Rounds Talk, Text, Overheads, Notes, 1999-04-16 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "American Foundations and the Development of Modern Biomedicine in Europe" at Rockefeller Archive Center, 1999-07-18-1999-07-19 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Carnegie Institution in Washington, 2000-02 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - IRB Talk, 2000-04 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - STS Talk - Public as A Partner, 2000-12-01 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - DNA Science Tuscon Talk, 2001-01 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - "The Public as a Partner in Scientific Research" Talk, 2001-07-17 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - NORD Talks, 2005-09-30-2005-10-01 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Witness Seminar Information Notes and Arrangements, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Shaping Scientific Research, Budapest, 2009-07 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Black History Month Talk, 2010-01-26 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - MLK Talk Genomic Medicine, 2013-01 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - American Society of Human Genetics Submission, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Smithsonian Talk "Real Life Genome Stories", 2013-11-21 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - ASBH Panel, 2014-10 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Psychiatry Grand Rounds Carilion, 2016-11 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Butterflies to Blood Talk and Overheads (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Liverpool School Overheads (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Inter. Soc. for the History Philosophy and Social Studies of Biology at Brandeis University, 1993-07 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Conference Professional Obligations and Policy, 2001-10 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Poster from Fetal ABO Blood Group Typing Using Amniotic Fluid Talk, 1989 (Box 10)
- Series III. Book Reviews, 1982-2010
  - Science and Morality, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Does it Run in the Family?, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Does It Run In the Family" Figures (Oversize Folder 1)
  - To Test or Not to Test?, 2008-2010 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Vignetts as an Aid to Deciding About Genetic Testing Poster, 2008 (Oversize Folder 1)
- Series IV. Background Information on Published Papers, 1980-2008
  - Clinical Genetics paper, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation and French Research, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Zallen and Burian on "The Beginnings of Somatic Cell Hybridization, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation and Spectroscopy Research, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Zallen "The 'Light' Organism for the Job", 1993 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Testimony from the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Human Genome Therapy, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Gayon and Zallen "The Role of Vilmorin Company...1840-1920", 1998 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Financial Times Viewpoint, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Butterflies to Blood, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Welcome Witness Seminar on "Genetic Testing", 2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Trends in Genetics, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Nature Letter to the Editor "Despite Franklin's work Wilkins earned his Nobel", 2003 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Encyclopedia of the Human Genome, 2003, 2015 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Burian and Zallen "Genes", 2008 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Louis Rapkine Articles, 1945-1991 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    Related Materials
    Related information can be found in Series II, the Bertrand Goldschmidt folder and Rene Wurmser folder.
  - Zallen "Redrawing the Boundaries of Molecular Biology: The Case of Photosynthesis", 1952-1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series V. Ethics Advisory Board, 1979-05-04
  - Report and Conclusions: HEW Support of Research Involving Human In Vitro Fertilization and Embryo Transfer, 1979-05-04 (Box 10)
  - Appendix: HEW Support of Research Involving Human In Vitro Fertilization and Embryo Transfer, 1979-05-04 (Box 10)
- Series VI. Liverpool School, 1952-2012
  - Overview and Publications, 1999-2018 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cyril A. Clarke, Autobiographical and Biographical Materials, 1995-2010 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cyril A. Clarke, Interview and List of Co-investigators, 1992-1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Turning Point, 1952-1956 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Clarke/Sheppard Butterfly Research, 1982-2003 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Rh Disease of Newborn, 1954-2011 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Nuffield Grant, 1963-1971 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Railway Bank Colony, 1988-1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Railway Bank Colony - Lawrence Cook, 1959-2003 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Genetics in Medicine, 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Philip Sheppard Papers, 1953-2011 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Philip Sheppard Tape, 1968 (Box 13)
    Philip Sheppard gives a brief account of the prevention of Rh haemolytic disease. It was provided to DTZ by Daphne Christie on 22 July 2004 as part of the Wellcome Witness Seminar materials.
  - Fo Clarke Materials, 1978-1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Clarke Family Correspondence, 2010-2012 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Clarke-Zallen Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, 1960-1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Interview transcripts, correspondence, and research
    - Ronald Finn, 1962-1998 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Richard McConnell, 1960-2004 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - David Price Evans Interview, 1957-1998 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - David Weatherall Interview, 1991-1998 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - John Woodrow Interview, 1962-1998 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Rodney Harris Interview, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Peter Harper Interview, 1985-1998 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Marcus Pembrey Interview, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Victor McKusick Interview, 1996-2001 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Sally Thompson and Angela Urion Interview, 2010-2012 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Other Interviews, 1998-2001 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      These interviews are dditional contacts made at the suggestion of David Price Evans and Cyril Clarke. Only DTZ interview notes are available. The interivews that David Price recommended were Cohen, Connor, Cooper, and Rodeck; the interviews that Cyril Clark recommended was Towers.
    - D.A. Ritchie Interview, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - A. D. Bradshaw Interview, 1972-1998 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Geoffrey Harrison Interview, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - David Hopkinson Interview, 1964-1998 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Ursula Mittwoch Interview, 1994-2002 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Lawrence Cook Interview, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Arthur Cain Interview, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Lawrence Cook Correspondence, 1988-1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - David West Interview, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Bruce Grant Interview, 1992-2010 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Interview tapes
    - Ronald Finn Interview Tape, 1998-04-23 (Box 13)
    - Richard McConnell Interview Tape, 1998-05-06 (Box 13)
    - David Price Evans Tape, 1998-04-22 (Box 13)
    - David Weatherall Interview Tape, 1998-04-17 (Box 13)
    - Peter Harper Interview Tape, 1998-05-28 (Box 13)
    - Marcus Pembrey Interview Tape, 1998-04-16 (Box 13)
    - Victor McKusick Interview Tape (Box 13)
    - D. A. Ritchie, 1998-05-07 (Box 13)
    - A. D. Bradshaw Interview Tape, 1998-05-07 (Box 13)
    - David Hopkinson Interview Tape, 1998-04-24 (Box 13)
    - Cyril Clarke Interview Tape, 1991-05-21 (Box 13)
    - Cyril Clarke and Lady Clarke Interview Tape, 1992-02-08 (Box 13)
    - David Weatherall Interview Tape, 1991-05-03 (Box 13)
    - Rene Wurmser Interview Tape, 1991-06-26 (Box 13)